If this administration and any of the previous administrations truly cared about the so-called migration crises, they would stop causing it.
It would stop intervening politically, economically, and militarily in the affairs of other nations.
But it won't, because waging war at home and abroad is more profitable for the billionaires signing their checks.
War in any of its forms has never been for the benefit of the people.
And as the Trump administration wages war against the people of the United States, making billions for private companies, it is also waging war against the people of the world.
Last week, it declared Cuba a national threat.
Let's be clear. Cuba poses no threat to the United States.
But for 67 years, the U.S. has strangled the Cuban economy, stealing nearly $15 million a day from the Cuban people.
And now it tightens its news.
Let's explore the level of hypocrisy.
Our communities are being militarized.
Civilians are being kidnapped without due process, taken from their jobs, from their homes, from their cars, and forced into concentration camps.
Over 30 people have died in ICE custody this year alone.
Children as young as two are being held in deplorable conditions.
At least eight people have been shot and killed.
We see the videos and we hear them lie to justify their crimes.
We live in a country where brutal force normalizes racism, hatred for immigrants, for trans people, for women, where dissent is met with violence, where journalists are arrested for telling the truth.
And this is not new.
It's accelerating and it's intensifying.
So we must ask ourselves, what authority does this morally bankrupt government have to impose its will on any other nation to violate the sovereignty and self-determination of people from other countries?
None.
They have no moral or legal authority.
You can be sure they're not about democracy.
They're not about freedom.
Their God is profit.
The only authority they claim is violence, is occupation, is extraction, the enslavement of other countries and their people.
And with this, they produce mass migration.
This is the legacy.
Think slavery.
Think Jim Crow.
Mass incarceration.
Think ICE.
Think of how we, the people of this country, are denied the most basic things.
Health care, education, how they create scapegoats but never solve the problem.
How they force working people into debt for survival on stagnant, unlivable wages.
For 67 years, the U.S. has punished Cuba for choosing to be free from its intervention.
The world has denounced this for over 30 years.
Cuba should not be punished for choosing not to be part of and complicit with the atrocities that we know the U.S.
government administrations have been capable of.
We don't need to agree in order to respect.
But the United States government does not abide by that simple ethical standard.
And now they label Cuba a national threat.
Why?
Because Cuba, again, chose freedom and dignity.
Because Cuba chose doctors over bombs.
Because Cuba's existence proves another way is possible.
And that is the greatest threat of all.
Proving that it is possible to be free from imperialism.
I am not Cuban.
Because I know you're going to come for me.
And I don't need to be in order to know what the U.S. has in store for the Cuban people if they get their way.
I was born in the most exploited congressional district in this country, the South Bronx.
I am a working class black Caribbean woman, a daughter of immigrants.
And that is why I have the right and I have the responsibility to say this.
They are using our resources, our taxes.
Yes.
And our silence to launch wars on Cuba, Venezuela, Palestine, and so many other countries.
We don't need trillions for war.
We need dignified wages.
We need health care.
We need housing.
We need education.
We need ICE abolished.
And we demand that the U.S. government gets its hands off Cuba, gets its hands off Latin America and the Caribbean.
Let them develop within their right to sovereignty.
Our struggle is one struggle and our enemy is the same.
So U.S. hands of Cuba, hands of the world, people of the world, unite.